dulux.co.uk 2019-04-26

# Privacy Statement | Dulux

This is the Privacy Statement of the website [www.dulux.co.uk](http://www.dulux.co.uk/) ( **"Website"** ). This site is operated and maintained by the AkzoNobel entity referred to in the "Website Owner" section of this website (hereafter **"Dulux or "we"** ). AkzoNobel UK is the controller of the processing of all personal data collected through this website.

We want to give you the best **Dulux** experience possible. We use the information you share with us to make our services and your experience even better. This Privacy Statement aims to give you a clear view of how we may use your personal data, our dedication to protect your data and the options you have to control your personal data and protect your privacy.

This Privacy Statement may be changed over time. Users of the Website are advised to regularly review the Privacy Statement for possible changes. This Privacy Statement was last changed on **05-11-2015.**

This Privacy Statement can be stored or printed using the buttons at the top of this page.

### When is this Privacy Statement applicable?

This Privacy Statement is applicable to the processing of personal data of users through this Website.

### For what purpose do we process your personal data?

We use your personal data for a number of different purposes. You will find an overview of the types of personal data and the purposes for which these are used below.

  *  **When you use our Website or Apps, to deliver you the Website or App and for the technical and functional management of the Website.**  
We process technical data such as your IP-address, the internet browser you use, the visited webpages, previous/next visited websites and the duration of a visit for the purposes of delivering the functionalities of the Website to allow to find the information in a quick and simple manner. This data is also used for resolving technical difficulties or for improving accessibility of certain parts of the website. For this purpose we also use cookies [read more] (/en/cookies)

  *  **When you open a Dulux account with us, to administer the account and to ensure confidentiality and security of your purchases.**

##### What does the purpose entail?

When you choose to register with us, you need to provide personal data such as your name, a valid email address and any other information requested, so that we can create a personal account for you. Upon creating your account, we will send you your personal login information. These personal data enable us to administer your account and enable us to ensure the confidentiality and maintain the security of your purchases. We also process data such as your display name, your role and your login data. We are, for instance, able to change your password for you. We are, however, not able to view your password.

  *  **When you purchase products through our web shop, to process your order and for customer service and relationship management**

##### What does this purpose entail?

When you use our web shop services, we use personal data to service your purchase and deliver your order, report the status of your order and when a transaction has failed, we use personal data to contact you about the transaction. For this we need at least your name and geographical address, contact details such as telephone number or e-mail address, credit card or other payment information, your acceptance of our applicable terms and conditions, and whether or not you want to receive our newsletter. We also process information about what you have purchased from us. When you contact us through our contact form on the Website, by e-mail or otherwise, we will use your contact information, your correspondence with us about your question and all other personal data provided by you in order to answer your question.

  *  **For the development and improvement of products and services**

##### What does this purpose entail?

We use aggregated personal data to analyse customer behaviour and to adjust our products and services accordingly, to ensure that it is relevant to our customers. This means that we analyse how often you read our newsletters, how often you visit our Website, which pages you click on and what goods you purchase through our website. Based on this information, we can make adjustments to our offering, our newsletters or our Website. We may also adapt our promotions on the basis of our analysis. We may also perform research into market trends through statistical analysis to evaluate and adapt our products and marketing to new developments, but research results are only reported on an aggregated basis. We may purchase supplementary data from public sources to complement our database for the above purposes.

 **Your choices**

  *  **If you participate in prize contests, events, competitions, promotions and/or games of chance, to administer your participation**

##### What does this purpose entail?

With your consent, we can send you emails with promotions and invitations to participate in a prize contests, events, competitions or games of chance. If you choose to participate in one of these activities, we need your personal data to be able to announce and organise these. Also, if you participate in any of these activities, we need your personal data to announce when you are a winner, to distribute the prizes and to measure the response to prize contests, events, competitions, promotions and or games of chance. For this, we process your name, address, email address and your entries in the activity.

  *  **Only if you have consented to this during your account registration, for sending you personalized information about AkzoNobel**

##### What does this purpose entail?

You may choose to receive personalised commercial messages, including a personalised newsletter, from AkzoNobel that are tailored towards your personal preferences. For this we will create profiles and analyze your interactions with us. We will look at personal data such as: - your name, gender, date of birth, e-mail address, and physical address; - your preferences and interests, such as those that you have actively shared with us, but also those inferred through your registered interactions with AkzoNobel websites and apps (for which we may use cookies); - your shopping history, both online (if you link your purchases to your profile) and offline (when making an offline purchase) ; and - the links you click in our emails.

This way we learn about your interests and can ensure that we provide you with the information and promotions that are of most interest to you. We may also ask you for your opinion about our products and services. If you don’t want to receive any more messages or if you want to opt-out of receiving or seeing a particular form of communication with us (for example SMS, social media, e-mail or regular mail), just, follow the steps in that particular communication.

### Who has access to your data?

We treat your data with care and confidentiality and do not share your data with third parties other than as explicitly addressed in this Privacy Statement.

  *  **With other entities within the AkzoNobel group**  
We may share pseudonimised or anonymised, or aggregated information about our consumers with other members of the AkzoNobel Group, for example to be used for trend analysis. The relevant group members are: Akzo Nobel Decorative Coatings B.V. and Akzo Nobel Coatings International B.V. together with all their direct or indirect subsidiaries operating in the business of decorative paints worldwide through the trading brands Dulux (Valentine), Trimetal, Coral, Flexa, Hammerite, Marshall, Sadolin, Alabastina, Astral, Levis, Corona, International Paints.

  *  **With service providers**  
We use various companies which process data on our behalf, such as hosting companies, delivery services, payment providers and credit scoring agencies. These companies use your information on our behalf, and are subject to strict rules they need to adhere to in order to process your information. We do not allow such companies to use the data in any other way than as per our instructions.

  *  **Other 3rd parties**  
We may need to disclose personal information at the request of governmental or law enforcement agencies. We will only further share your information only with other companies or individuals when we have your valid consent to do so.

### How to treat links to other websites and social media?

##### External websites

On the Website you will find a number of links to other websites. Although these websites are selected with care, we are not responsible for the processing of your personal data through these websites. Our [Terms and Conditions] (/en/terms-and-conditions) and this Privacy Statement are therefore not applicable to the use of such websites.

##### Social media

Our Website and Apps may provide you with social plug-ins from various social networks. If you choose to interact with a social network (for example by registering an account), your activity on our Website or via our Apps will also be made available to social networks such as Facebook and Twitter.

If you are logged in on one of these social networks during your visit to one of our Websites or Apps, the social network might add this information to your respective profile on this network. If you are interacting with one of the social plug-ins, this information will be transferred to the social network. In case you do not wish such a data transfer, please log off from your social network before you enter one of our Websites or Apps.

We also offer the opportunity to create an account with us through your social network account (such as Facebook). This will save you time in creating the account, as your sign-on credentials will be imported from your social network account. Please note that when you use this "social sign-on" option, we may receive certain information via the social network, such as your name, age, location, preferences, occupation, and other information from your public profile, and possibly also access to your pictures or lists of your friends on the social network. This information is not requested by us, but is provided by the social network through the use of the social sign-on option. When you use the social sign-on option, we will only import the information that is necessary for the creation of your account with us and will, upon receipt of any other information, discard that information received through the social network. After having created your account, you will have the opportunity to supplement it with any information you want to share with us.

Your social media platform will show you AkzoNobel advertisements through its social media pages to the extent you have allowed this via the privacy settings of your social media provider

Please read the privacy policies of those social networks for detailed information about the collection and transfer of personal data, what rights you have and how you can achieve satisfactory privacy settings.

### How do we secure the data?

Your personal data is treated strictly confidentialy and we have taken the appropriate technical and organisational security measures against loss or unlawful processing of this data. To this purpose we use several security techniques including secure servers, firewalls and encryption, as well as physical safeguard of the locations where data are stored.

#### Retention of the data

We will not retain your personal data for a period longer than is necessary for achieving the purposes for which they were collected, or as long as the law prescribes.

### Request/Deletion/Correction of your Personal Data

By clicking on this [link](https://www.dulux.co.uk/en/contact-us) and completing the contact us form, you will be able to request one of the following:

  * Request a copy of the personal data we hold.
  * Request for deletion of your personal data.
  * Request to correct any of your personal data.
